<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Jiangyan Feng</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Jiangyan Feng © 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/jiangyanfeng</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Molecular Dynamics Simulations of Nutrient Transport in Plants</title>
      <link>/project/transporters/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/transporters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We focus on developing and employing machine learning, data science, and molecular modelling techqniues to understand the complex dynamic mechanisms of transporter proteins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three key components:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Performing large-scale all-atom molecular dynamics simulations on petascale supercomputer to unravel the molecular mechanisms of 3 different transporters (plant nitrate transporter NRT1.1, bacteria nitrate/nitrite antiporter NarK, and bacteria nitrate symporter NarU).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Constructing Markov State Models to analyze high-dimensional and long-timescale simulation data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developing and employing state-of-the-art machine learning and data science techniques (e.g. genetic algorithm, dimensionality reduction, feature selection, clustering, and cross-validation) to optimize parameters for Markov State Models constructions and to extract insights from high dimensional data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimization of Neural Network Convolution Layer through Parallel Programming</title>
      <link>/project/parallel_programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/parallel_programming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We employed parallel programming optimization approaches for designing and implementing an optimized neural network convolution layer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are four major optimizations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kernel fusion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimizing grid and block dimensions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unrolling the for loop using restrict and pragma unroll.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimizing tile width for tiled matrix multiplication.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning for Protein Dynamics Prediction</title>
      <link>/project/ml_ecs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/ml_ecs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Proteins are dynamic molecules which perform diverse molecular functions by adopting different three-dimensional structures. Recent progress in coevolution contacts prediction opens up new avenues for the de novo protein structure prediction from sequence information. However, it is still difficult to predict more than one conformation from coevolution contacts alone. This is due to the inability to deconvolute the complex signals of coevolution contacts, i.e. spatial contacts relevant for protein folding, conformational diversity, and ligand binding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, we introduce a machine learning based method, called FingerprintContacts, for extending the capabilities of coevolution contacts. We demonstrate the capabilities of FingerprintContacts on four ligand binding proteins with varying conformational motions. Furthermore, FingerprintContacts identifies small clusters of coevolution contacts which are preferentially located in the dynamically fluctuating regions. With the rapid growth in protein sequence information, we expect FingerprintContacts to be a powerful first step in structural understanding of protein functional mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pattern Discovery from DNA Sequences</title>
      <link>/project/pattern_discover/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/pattern_discover/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We developed a “motif finding” program to discover patterns in DNA sequences and tested it against the benchmark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three major components:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Building a benchmark.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implementing the “motif finder”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evaluating the motif finder on the benchmark and making intelligent inferences.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic Feature Selection for Dimensionality Reduction</title>
      <link>/project/ga/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/ga/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Markov State Models (MSMs) are a powerful framework to reproduce the long-time conformational dynamics of biomolecules using a set of short Molecular Dynamics (MD) simulations. However, precise kinetics predictions of MSMs heavily rely on the features selected to describe the system. Despite the importance of feature selection for large system, determining an optimal set of features remains a difficult unsolved problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, we introduce an automatic approach to optimize feature selection based on genetic algorithms (GA), which adaptively evolves the most fitted solution according to natural selection laws. The power of the GA-based method is illustrated on long atomistic folding simulations of four proteins, varying in length from 28 to 80 residues. Due to the diversity of tested proteins, we expect that our method will be extensible to other proteins and drive MSM building to a more objective protocol.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
